

# **Jaymil Vyas**

#### Senior Data Associate

**Phone:** 9510181016

Address: A-702, Swati Gardenia, Torrent Power Sub Station Road, Makarba, Ahmedabad-

380051

**Website:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaymil-vyas-345b5220

https://github.com/JaymilVyas

**Email**: jaymilvyas@gmail.com

Experienced Sr. Data Associate with over 9 years of experience working with an MNC offering in-depth essential data and insights to customers. Veteran 'people manager- operations' with demonstrated leadership abilities, strategic planning expertise, and problem-solving acumen while carrying a 'client-first' as well as 'people-first' mindset. Astute, calculating, and attentive to specific business requirements. Successful history of identifying patterns, making interpretations, and producing reports. Skills in setting up databases and other frameworks, managing systems, and aligning procedures with business needs. Ready to tackle new challenges and build success with an exciting organization.

#### EXPERIENCE

### **S&P Global Market Intelligence**

May 2022 To Present

#### Senior Data Associate

- Assists in analyzing complex data sets to provide insights, conclusions, and actionable recommendations.
- Participates in performing complex analysis through an understanding of how to integrate multiple systems and data sets; suggests a collection of new data and refinement of existing data.
- Gains a broad understanding of products, services or technologies that drive business and integrates complex data for new insights.
- Provides higher-level data management and operations support for a range of datasets, products, and/or groups. Works closely with project teams to identify and suggest process enhancements and operational changes across businesses.
- Assists in designing new process guidelines, and write business procedures and training materials. Assists in implementation plans and stakeholder communications.
- Works with internal teams to integrate and manage data from other sources.
- Assists in tracking quantitative and qualitative metrics to measure data management. Provides fact-based interpretation and analysis of findings and knowledge-based recommendations to manage data more efficiently.
- Interact with internal and external clients as necessary and occasionally works on new projects and data enhancement initiatives as assigned.
- Learn new skills and apply them to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity. Utilize advanced querying, visualization, and analytics tools to analyze and process complex data sets.
- Discovered stories told by data to present information to scientists and business managers. Develop polished visualizations to share the results of data analyses.

# **S&P Global Market Intelligence**

June 2021 To Apr. 2022

### **Assistant Manager**

- Manage more than one operation support team/group for a range of data/content management activities. Ensure team
  members are compliant when conducting data/information collection through thorough knowledge of guidelines, policies,
  and research tools.
- Responsible for the day-to-day workflow management and performance of more than one team to ensure accuracy and
  efficiency of process workflows.
- Manages the performance review process, talent development, and talent management processes of the team. Identifies individual strengths to appropriately delegate work amongst the team. Guide and coach team members for future growth.
- Interact with internal and external clients as necessary and occasionally works on new projects and data enhancement initiatives as assigned.
- Deliver Strong Business Health and Performance, Manage Full-Time Employee (FTE) Costs. Drive Integration and Operational Synergies with FTE Integration Savings Return to Business.
- Encourage Open Communication and Transparency Globally. Support Coverage Expansion of Customer-Focused Projects.
- Foster and Encourage Diversity & Inclusion; Attract, Develop, Engage, and Retain Top and Emerging Talent. Pursue

### **Created using Resumonk - Online Resume Builder**

Operational Excellence - Innovation and LEAN, Enhance Technology - Workflow & Collection Tools.

• Drive Data Quality Operational Mindset, Improve Per Capita Productivity. Deliver Customer-Focused Domain Projects, Improve Customer Experience with Data Organization.

June 2010 To May 2012

Jun 2007 To May 2010

## **S&P Global Market Intelligence**

- Team Leader (Apr. 2019 To May 2021)
- Sr. Data Researcher-II (Apr. 2018 To Mar. 2019)
- Sr. Data Researcher-I (Oct. 2016 To Mar. 2018)
- Data Researcher-III (Feb. 2016 To Sep. 2016)

### SNL Financial India Pvt. Ltd.

- Senior Analyst-I (Oct. 2014 To Jan. 2016)
- Analyst (Dec. 2012 To Sep. 2014)

#### **EDUCATION**

### M.S. University, Tirunelveli

**MBA** 

Marks Obtained: 70%

Primary: Finance | Secondary: Marketing

## **Gujarat University**

**BAchelor of Science** 

Marks Obtained: 62%

Primary: Physics | Secondary: Mathematics

#### SKILLS

- High-Level Understanding of Databases
- · Data Extraction, Transformation, and Loading
- Data Visualization and Storytelling
- Critical Thinking and Effective Communication
- Business Acumen
- Proactive Problem Solving
- Ability To Listen, Trust, and Relate
- Strong Organizational Skills- Work Prioritization
- Meet Established Deadlines & Time Management
- Strong In Coordinating For Interdepartmental Projects
- Ability to Manage Multiple Priorities At Once
- Proven Ability To Work With Minimal Direction
- Highly Motivated, Aggressive, Detail Oriented

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python Programming, MySQL and SQL Server, Tableau and Power BI, Advance M.S. Excel, GitHub, DBMS (SQL & No-SQL)

#### **INTERSETS**

Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Photography, Travelling